Can't focus. My body is still puzzled about what to do.
Shuuchuu dekitenaina mada karada ga mayotteirunda
I'm trembling. I can't stop even if I try to control myself.
Furueteitanja kontoroorushitatte burerunda
Although neither sun nor moon are on my side,
Taiyou mo tsuki mo nanmo kanzen ni kocchi muiteinaiga
"I've no choice but to try,"
Yarushikanainda
Those were the words I muttered to myself.
Iikikaseruyouni sotto tsubuyaita
The odds aren't on my side, but running way'd be gutless.
Joukyou wa waruiga tada nigedasunja konjou nainaa
Even if I can't see the future, I'll just have to win it over with courage.
Tenbou wa naiga dokyou de kuria suru shika naiya
Need to keep distance from the target as I hold myself back.
Shoudou wa osaetamama taagetto to no kankaku sagure
All that's needed for victory is pride to win.
Hitsuyou na mon wa katsu puraido
Will we celebrate with the wine of victory
Ajiwau nowa shouri no bishu ka
Or'll we end up kissing their feet in defeat?
Soretomo haiboku no kujuu ka
There are two outcomes to everything.
Sou subete wa futatsu ni hitotsu
I want to control destiny.
Ayatsuritai unmei no ito
I need to seize the golden opportunity with my hands.
Zekkou no goorudentaimu kono te de tsukame
I'll finish it up with my best poker face,
Konshin no pookaafeisu kimete shikakeruyo
And drag them into a world of illusions.
Iryuujon no sekai e hikizurikonde
I'll find my way out of this endless pressure game,
Saigennai puresshaageemu sururito nukete
And leap over the borderline of honor.
Eikou no boodaarain tobikoeru tameni
How many? What'll I need to sacrifice to make it happen?
Haumenii? Dorekurai no daishou ga iru?
What is the one thing I don't want to let go?
Tebanashitakunai mon wa dore?
Ed and Al were searching for May, a girl from Xing, to find out more about Eastern Alchemy.
They are now headed north after learning she was headed in that direction.
At the same time, Kimblee, the Crimson Alchemist, is after Scar, who had just left Central and is now westbound.
But Scar suddenly disappeared in the darkness of the night.
If they were to jump off the train, it would surely be around here, where the track is full of curves,
since the engine would decelerate.
Now the question is, where did they go after they jumped off?
Have there been any sighting reports on Scar?
None at all, sir...
That's very strange.
He had been attracting a lot of attention up until this point.
Reporting in, sir!
A small boat by the river has been stolen about 200 meters south of here!
Was it Scar?
There haven't been any sightings so far.
Go investigate.
Roger!
Reporting in, sir!
We've received a report from an old man, who lives in the area, of two suspicious-looking men heading westbound.
Now they're heading west?
Send some men over and capture those two immediately!
Roger!
Is something the matter?
No, it's just that...
There's a mountain trail on this map that heads north.
Why is it crossed out?
There used to be a path through
the forest to get to the northern area,
but it's been closed down due to landslides.
What about the path, sir?
There are several other places beyond this point that have been closed off due to landslides.
It looks like the stream has moved.
It seems so... but are you saying it means something?
For an alchemist skilled in destruction, removing an obstacle such as this is a walk in the park.
It's also simple to destroy the surface of a mountain and to block off the road with the rocks.
Signs of transmutation?!
Send the troops north.
The Northern Wall
of Briggs
Snow!
Brother!
Geez, you're so fidgety!
Shut up, I just slipped.
Man, look at all the snow!
Yeah. We rarely see snow in Resembool.
Oh yeah, Al.
Do you remember when it snowed heavily in Resembool when we were kids?
Heavy snowfall?
Oh, I remember now!
We had a snowball fight!
We made a snowman, too, remember?
Yeah!
Back then, I never would have thought that I'd come this far north...
But we did, didn't we?
Well, what to do now?
We've still got time until the train to Briggs departs.
Why don't you go eat something nice?
I'm not really hungry...
But I guess I'll go see what's on the menu!
Hey! If you start running, you'll slip again!
Shut up!
Yes. Three hours ago...
Scar's description, document number, and...
Any new information so far?
We're trying our best, but we haven't found anything yet.
A man matching Scar's description was sighted at the marshalling yard at the next station.
Is this confirmed?
Yes, sir.
He was last seen climbing into
a troop transport headed for Briggs.
Was there anyone with him?
A middle-aged man with black hair.
Matches the initial report perfectly.
We'll have the train stopped immediately.
There's no need for that.
It would be troublesome if they leap off again.
I'll take over from here.
Please don't interfere with my work.
Sleep for now.
When we get further north, you'll have
a hard time sleeping because of the cold.
I'm jumping over. Please try to match the speed of the other train.
Yes, sir!
Dr. Marcoh.
I've come to pick you up.
You've got nowhere else to run.
Are you alone?
Where is Scar?
You just don't know when to quit, do you?
Didn't I just say you had nowhere else to run, Doctor Mar-
Who are you?
So you're the Ishbalan everyone's talking about...
You can't expect me to put up with those monsters!
Now's my chance to jump off...
Impossible...
Solf J. Kimblee. The Crimson Alchemist.
Do you remember me?
Yes. Very clearly, in fact.
You were in the Kanda district of Ishbal.
Was it your family that was around you at the time?
I believe there was someone who closely resembled you, but with glasses.
Bleeding heavily from his left abdomen...
...and writhing in pain...
This isn't good.
I'm rusty from being in jail for all this time, but he's been fighting since the civil war.
In terms of stamina, I'm at a disadvantage.
However, all he can do is destroy-
Left abdomen, was it?
I won't give you the time to pray.
It's... a shame...
That I'd fail to kill the same Ishbalan twice...
How humiliating that I have to run away...
We'll settle the match next time, Ishbalan!
Kimblee!!!
Dammit, I can't see!
What the hell was that noise?
One of the cars is missing!
We can't! We've been ordered by the army not to stop the train!
No, we have to!
It'll be our fault if the train derails!
What... happened to you?!
Hey!
Who the hell said you could stop the train?!
What?!
Keep the train running.
Head north!
Good... death is chasing me.
Ones who kill are also chased by death.
Always living alongside death...
Jobs that risk one's soul are truly beautiful!
How rewarding...
My battlefield!
I wonder if Mr. Scar and Mr. Yoki are all right?
Since no one has come after us yet, it must mean they're doing a good job drawing the army's attention.
I hope they're safe.
Dr. Marcoh?
No, it's just that...
The northern wind is painful against healing skin.
Sorry. I wish I could have healed it to make it look a little better...
No, the face fits me well.
I'm happy with it.
Take a look, May.
Wow!
They're the Briggs Mountains.
The mountain range that serves as the border between our country and Drakma.
We should be close to the location Scar pointed out...
Let's see...
We're almost there!
Huh? He checked out of the hotel?
Yes, just yesterday.
Do you know where he went?
If I recall correctly, he said that they were headed north...
I see...
Thanks.
That idiot...
What's wrong? Were they doing well?
He said they headed north in that state.
Oh, my! He's totally...
...gonna die.
Did you catch a cold, Brother?
So cold...
It's Briggs, all right.
We're here, boys.
If you follow this mountain path, you'll get to the Briggs fortress.
Thanks.
Oh yeah, you.
Me?
Yeah, you.
That's not an automail, is it?
Nope.
Oh. Then you should be fine.
What was that about?
No idea.
Everything beyond that fence is owned by the army,
so you'll die if you stray from the path!
Huh?
Let's go!
Yeah.
They say the weather changes rapidly in the mountains, but I never expected something like this...
What should we do, Brother?
We've completely lost our way.
Don't worry!
Master Izumi was thrown into the Briggs Mountains in the winter for a month for her training, and she still survived.
There's no way that could be true!
How could someone survive for a month out here?!
But she said she defeated a bear, too!
The bears at Briggs grow to a height of up to two meters!
Who'd be able to defeat one?
A bear!!!
That's not a bear!
Al!
Hey, hang on!
You're wearing a military uniform!
You have an automail, too?
Just an ordinary one, it seems.
Yours is just plain ugly!
How foolish of you to not understand the beauty of this arm!
Combat Model Automail M1913-A Crocodile.
Surrender if you don't want to be ripped to shreds, Drakman spy!
Spy?
What the hell are you talking about? I'm...
Why, you...
Can't you be a little more understanding, oaf?
What is this pain?
My automail isn't moving very well!
You're mine!
Brother!
You bastard...
Just listen to me!
You're still going to resist?!
Are you serious?!
Wait! Wait! Wait! Just listen!!
Your useless automail is mine!
More like, your  arm is mine!
Did you do something?
Time out! Time out! Time out! Seriously! Time out!
Why doesn't alchemy work?!
This isn't made out of iron?!
Brother!
Thanks, Al!
Are you okay?
That freak...
I would've been killed by Winry before I froze to death out here.
Not bad, brat.
You did well for having a regular automail.
But this is it for you.
What?
Security personnel from Briggs?!
Geez, at gunpoint again?
Brother.
A wall?
What's the matter, Captain Buccaneer?!
I'm sorry for causing such a commotion, Major General Armstrong!
Armstrong?
So that's the person Major Armstrong wanted to introduce to us...
...Olivier Mira Armstrong?
Major Armstrong's sister!
But...
She looks nothing like him.
She's not huge.
Who the hell are you?
Edward Elric, the Fullmetal Alchemist.
I came to see you, Major General, with a letter of introduction from Major Armstrong from Central.
Please get these guys off of us, first!
Perform a full body check!
What?!
We're not suspicious in the least bit!
How should I know?
Anyone can pretend to be someone well-known.
What?! There's no one in here?!
That bitch...
Hm? This is...
Ma'am!
That's the letter from Major Alex Louis Armstrong.
If you read it, you'll know that we're not suspicious at all.
It really is from Alex.
You're not even going to read it?!
Testimonials mean nothing to me.
I don't need assessments made by others.
I'll judge you with my own eyes.
A-Amazing.
It's huge...
What the hell is this?!
Come in, Fullmetal Alchemist.
Awesome! It's so tall! It's huge!
Hurry up and walk, laggards.
Want me to rip that antenna off your head?
I'll tell you this now. I won't be treating you like a kid.
This is Briggs, the land of natural defense.
A world where the weak are victims of the strong.
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
We used to talk all night until the sun rose,
Asahi ga noboru made katariattane
And held hands till the sun went under the horizon.
Yuuhi ga shizumu made tsunaida te
Let's walk together like this forever, like light and shadow.
Kouyatte asu mo asatte mo tomo ni ayumou hikari to kage
I stand in the city, staring off into space with lonely eyes.
Samishige ni mitsumeru machi no naka de
I can't find warmth on my own.
Nukumori wa hitori ja mitsukaranakute
By meeting you, I realized
Ai ga konnani tsuyosa ni narukoto
How much strength love could give me.
Shittanda kimi ni deaete hajimete
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
And let us bring light to the night sky with no stars.
Hoshi no yoru mo terashitsuzukeyou
So long as you're with me, I can go to world's end.
Doko made mo yukeru kimi to nara
Even if it's a path I can't walk on my own,
Hitori ja arukenai michi mo futari nara
If you're by my side, I can walk it while humming a tune.
Hanauta utainagara arukerunda
If we're together, the world is mine.
Kimi ga ireba shiawase
There it is!
So these are his brother's research documents.
A combination of the alchemies from Xing and Amestris.
I wonder if there's anything about immortality in here?
I hope there is.
Now, will this become a book of hope,
or will it turn out to be a book of despair...
Let's begin the analysis.
The general of Briggs, Olivier Mira Armstrong.
Fierce and powerful, she is Amestris' guardian of the north.
She has no fears, though there are many that fear her.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Ice Queen
Episode 34, Ice Queen.
This is how we do things in Briggs.